Lok To (Ray) Kwan

Markham, ON, L3R 6M8

(647) 210-3443 | lokto.kwan@gmail.com | github.com/kwanlokto

Summary

Results-driven and adaptive Senior Software Developer with a strong passion for innovation and continuous learning. Formally trained in **Computer Science** with **6 years** of professional experience developing for fast-paced, SaaS startup companies where his contributions had a significant impact on product features and direction. Ray excels at navigating complex codebases, improving code quality and implementing best practices. He is also a team player, praised by superiors for his exceptional communication and leadership skills in cultivating a high-performing and motivated team.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, Javascript (ES6+), Typescript, Java Framework/Library: React, Angular, Numpy, Pandas, SciPy

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis

DevOps: Docker, Linode, CI/CD Workflow: Agile, Microservices, REST

Work Experience

Skatescribe Markham, ON Senior Software Developer & Team Lead Oct 2023 - Present

- Led a team of 2 developers and 1 UI/UX designer to build critical features for our electron and web application
- Spearheaded the planning and development of a 6-month project leading to a 25% reduction in cycle time, enhanced user experience, a cleaner and more maintainable codebase, and improved data accuracy and reliability
- Collaborated with stakeholders and management to define technical roadmaps, break down requirements into actionable development tasks, and align timelines and scope to balance feasibility and impact
- Configured and managed containerized environments using Docker for consistent and scalable deployments
- Facilitated daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and retrospectives to ensure efficient workflow, conducted annual performance reviews, and provided ongoing feedback to support up-to-date best practices and professional growth
- Achieved: Strong leadership and communication skills to foster an efficient, motivated, and high-performing team

Full Stack Software Developer

May 2021 - Oct 2023

- Developed an **Electron** app that captures any skate blade's shape with 0.5µm accuracy using a laser profiler, enabling users to customize their blade's geometry with a 0.1µm tolerance on a Tormach CNC machine
- Prototyped a ReactJS-based web application for operators to record and track customer order history
- Applied Savitzky-Golay filtering and spline regression to enhance 2D blade images from the laser profiler, dynamically minimizing errors in approximating the noisy image with G1 continuous B-splines
- Implemented algorithms to convert B-splines into segments that can be processed by the CNC machine for cutting
- Achieved: The ability to work independently, research and apply new technologies, and take ownership of projects

Cognitive Centivizer

Full Stack Software Developer

University of Toronto Sept 2020 - May 2021

- Created a game **React** and **NodeJS** to collect and organize participant data to be used by psychology students
- Guided the team in implementing the best software practices, ensuring a consistent and maintainable codebase
- Achieved: Product improvement by aligning and strengthening development practices with the team

Autocase Toronto, ON May 2019 - April 2020

Full Stack Software Developer

Translated research models into an app that measures the costs and benefits of a building in AngularJS and Python

Created efficient and reliable python scripts to aggregate 150+ GB of NC/CSV files into pandas within 8 hrs

Education

Computer Science Specialist (CGPA: 3.61)

University of Toronto (2016 - 2021)